A Guide to the Jones Family Papers, 1788-1846
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Jones Family Papers, 1788-1846
Library of Virginia
22102
.15 cu. ft. (Negative photostats.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Augusta B. Fothergill, 1943.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joseph Jones was born 23 August 1749 in Petersburg, Virginia, the son of Thomas Jones (d. 1773) and Lucy Watson Jones. He was elected vestryman of Bristol Parish in 1773. Jones served as a captain in the Revolution, became a colonel in the Virginia militia in 1784, promoted to brigadier general in 1784, and elected major general in 1803. He served in the House of Delegates in 1787, and as a postmaster and collector of the port for Petersburg. He married first Ann Call (1761-1778) and had one child, and he married second Jane Atkinson in 1780 and had 10 children. Jones died 9 February 1824 at "Cedar Grove," his home in Dinwiddie County, Virginia. His oldest son by his second wife, Thomas Jones, was born 18 August 1781 at "Cedar Grove" and attended the College of William and Mary, where he earned an A.B. and B.L. Thomas married Mary Lee (1790-1848) 11 December 1804. Jones died 9 November 1866 at "Bell Vue" in Chesterfield County, Virginia. Joseph Jones's son and Thomas Jones's brother Joseph Jones was born 20 February 1787 in Petersburg. He studied medicine in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and became a doctor. He married first Sarah Bland Atkinson, and second, Mary Pickett of Kentucky. Joseph Jones moved west, dying in New Orleans, Louisiana, 29 August 1847. Thomas Jones's son Thomas was born 8 September 1811 at "Bell Vue." He married Anne Seymour Trowbridge of Westmoreland County, Virginia, 21 October 1843. First a Presbyterian minister, then a lawyer, Jones served as Westmoreland County's commonwealth's attorney from 1849 to 1869. He served as a judge from 1872 to 1893. He died 27 December 1893.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1788-1846, of the Jones family of Dinwiddie and Chesterfield Counties, and Petersburg, Virginia, consisting of personal and business correspondence to and from Joseph Jones (1749-1824), Thomas Jones (1781-1866), and Joseph Jones (1787-1847), discussing land and property in Virginia and Kentucky, education of children, politics, militia musters, agriculture, and inheritances. Includes: deeds, accounts, lists of slaves and livestock, powers of attorney, bonds, promissory notes, agreements, memorandums, and songs.
Contents List
- Letter. L[eighton] Wood, Richmond, to Colonel Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie, 26 March 1788., 1 p. (1 print)
- Deed. Erasmus Gill and Sarah, his wife, n.p., to Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, two lots in Town of Petersburg, dated 20 July 1789 and recorded Dinwiddie County, July 1790., 4 p. (4 prints)
- Deed. Roger Atkinson, Jr., and Agness, his wife, Chesterfield County, to Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, 500 acres in Halifax County, dated 20 October 1790 and recorded Halifax County, 25 October 1790., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. A. Buford, Richmond, to Colonel Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 10 May 1793., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. A. McRae, Richmond, to General Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie, 16 June 1793., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. John Stith, Brunswick County, to General Joseph Jones, Halifax County, 12 September 1795., 1 p. (1 print)
- Account of Joseph Jones with Chrisopher Jones, paid 21 March [17]97., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Benjamin Harrison, Brandon, to General Joseph Jones, Cedar Grove, [Town of Petersburg], 29 January 1798., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, n.p., to Alexander McRae, n.p., 22 June 1798., 1 p. (1 print)
- Deed. John Walsh, Halifax County, to Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, 263 acres in Halifax County, dated..., 4 p. (3 prints)
- Letters. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to [the professors of the College of William and Mary], 14 October 1798., 2 p. (3 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to [Brechen?], n.p., 10 March 1800., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. John [Verell?], Sterling Castle, to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 25 August 1800., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Deed. Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, to Donald Mackensie, Town of Petersburg, use of water, October 1803., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Cedar Grove, [Town of Petersburg], to Thomas Jones, Westmoreland County, 1 July 1805., 1 p. (1 print)
- Deed. Josiah Farler and Mary, his wife, to Joseph Jones, both parties of Dinwiddie County, 300 acres in Brunswick County, dated, 13 January 1809, and recorded Brunswick County, 26 March 1810., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Survey. 1,210 acres belonging to [Joseph Jones?], Halifax County, by James Eastham, Surveyor, 20 November 1810., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. A. Buford, Chilacothee [Chillacothe?], Ohio, to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 1 December 1810., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, n.p., to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 6 October 1812., 3 p. (2 prints)
- List of Negroes, 1813., 1 p. (1 print)
- List of cattle, etc., April 1813., 1 p. (1 print)
- Deed. Roger Atkinson and Agnes, his wife, to Thomas Jones, both parties of Chesterfield County, 2 1/3 acres in Chesterfield County, dated March 1814, and recorded Chesterfield County, 11 April 1814., 2 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, n.p., to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, [19 December 1816]., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Agreement. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, with Joseph Kidd, Brunswick County, 20 November 1817., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, n.p., to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 5 December 1817., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Power of attorney. Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, to Abraham Buford, Scott County, Kentucky, 14 May 1818., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. J[oseph] J[ones], Petersburg, to Colonel Abraham Buford, n.p., 26 May 1818., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Ohio, to Mrs. Jones, Cedar Grove, Petersburg, 2 August [1818?]., 2 p. (3 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to Colonel Abraham Buford, [Scott County, Kentucky], 16 May 1819., 2 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, n.p., to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 25 September 1819., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. A[braham] Buford, Scott County, Kentucky, to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, October 1819., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to Colonel [Abraham] Buford, n.p., 22 October 1819., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. A[braham] Buford, Scott County, Kentucky, to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 21 July 1821., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to Joseph Jones, n.p., 1 October 1821., 1 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to Joseph Jones, Halifax, 8 February 1822., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. A[braham] Buford, Scott County, [Kentucky], to General Joseph Jones, Petersburg, 14 June 1822., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Survey. 42 acres belonging to General Joseph Jones, Dinwiddie County, by James Hargrave, Surveyor, 28 June 1822., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Joseph Jones, Petersburg, to Colonel Abraham Buford, [Scott County, Kentucky], 14 July 1822., 1 p. (1 print)
- Contract. Joseph Jones with John Conway, both parties of Town of Petersburg, 22 September 1822., 1 p. (2 prints)
- Promissory notes. Thomas Jones to William B. Giles, 17 July 1826., 1 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. William B. Giles, Wigwam, to Thomas Jones, n.p., 2 August 1826., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Thomas Jones, Wigwam, to Thomas Jones, Petersburg, 6 May 1827., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Agreemtn among the children of Joseph Jones, deceased, 25 November 1828., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. James B. Jones, Mecklenburg, to Messrs. [Baird?], Thomas, Joseph, Roger and Benson Jones, n.p., 11 April 1829., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. A[braham] Buford, Scott County, Kentucky, to Joseph Jones, near Petersburg, 1 June 1833., 3 p. (2 prints) Incomplete.
- Letter. John Sims, Halifax, to Thomas Jones, Chesterfield, 17 January 1834., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Thomas J. Woodson, Knox County, Kentucky, to Thomas Jones or Joseph J. Anderson, Petersburg, 29 August 1834., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Deed. Thomas Jones, executor of Joseph Jones, deceased, n.p., to Henry Nollner, Town of Petersburg, lot in Petersburg, dated 22 April 1835, and recorded Town of Petersburg, 23 May 1835., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Bond. Benjamin W. Gates to Thomas Jones, 12 January 1838., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. Catherine MacDougall, Chesterfield, to Mrs. Jones Bellevue, n.p., 21 January 1844., 1 p. (1 print)
- Letter. M. E. Baugh, Portsmouth, to [Mrs. Mary Jones, Petersburg], 12 June 1846., 2 p. (1 print)
- Letter. M. Jones, n.p., to Thomas Jones, Bellevue, near Petersburg, 7 August [?]., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. Virginia [?], n.p., to Mrs. Mary Jones, Bellevue, [near Petersburg], 30 August [?]., 3 p. (2 prints)
- Memoranda for Joseph Jones from [?], n.d., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Letter. [?] to [?], n.d., 2 p. (2 prints)
- Song. "Blue Bonnets O'er the Border," n.d., 2 p. (2 prints)